# ALYSSA NYCUM

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# CONTACT INFORMATION



443-985-6423



alyssa.nycum@gmail.com

/in/alyssanycum/

/alyssanycum

alyssanycum.github.io/

#### **ABOUT ME**

Your not-so-average zoo keeper turned software developer.

For the last 10 years, I've had the incredible opportunity to work up close and personal with a wide variety of animals. But as priorities in life change, so do careers. As a natural problem-solver with a keen eye for details making the jump to software development wasn't as different from zoo keeping as you might think. Every day brings on new challenges and the idea of a lifetime of learning brings out an excitement in me that I look forward to continue exploring.

#### **EDUCATION**

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL, 2020

Full-Stack Software Development Bootcamp

**TOWSON UNIVERSITY, 2012** 

Bachelor of Science in Animal Behavior Bachelor of Science in Psychology

### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Full-Stack Software Developer**

Nashville Software School (Jan 2020 - Present)

Intensive, 6-month full-time software development bootcamp focusing on fullstack development fundamentals and problem solving through building individual and group projects

- Utilized Git and GitHub for version control
- Created websites and one-page applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React pulling data from 3rd party APIs and JSON server
- Learned JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular & readable code and reusable components
- Implemented full CRUD functionality triggered by user actions
- Gained experience learning and working on individual & group projects remotely
- Built a command line application in Python and will be learning SQL and Django framework

# **Individual Projects:**

#### BetaData

#### https://github.com/alyssanycum/betadata

- When it comes to climbing in an indoor rock climbing gym, climbs are constantly changing, and it can be difficult to keep track of which climbs you've already climbed. BetaData allows users to record the climbs they've done as well as any climbing goals they have. Users have full CRUD functionality on the climbs they record and can also add multiple attempts to a climb, add a helpful note about the climb, give each climb an enjoyment rating, filter & sort their climbs in multiple ways, and view charts that display how many climbs of each level they have done.
- Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, React.js, ReactStrap, Moment.js, Chart.js

# **Group Projects:**

#### **Handy Andy**

## https://github.com/alyssanycum/handyandy

- A social-media dashboard for people to use to organize their daily tasks, events, news articles, friends, and chat messages.
- Responsible for the news, settings, and logout functionality
- Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, React.js, React Semantic UI

#### Nutshell

# https://github.com/alyssanycum/nutshell

- The same project as Handy Andy but built using vanilla JavaScript
- Responsible for the events functionality
- Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

### **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

# **Hoofstock Keeper**

#### Nashville Zoo (Jun 2018 - December 2019)

- Worked with multiple teams to ensure the highest standard of animal care
- Utilized problem-solving skills and attention to detail to make animal management decisions
- Educated the public about animal care and conservation through keeper talks, behind the scenes tours, and training demos
- Expanded training programs by establishing multiple new behaviors for primary animals to increase cooperation and safety during routine veterinary check-ups
- Revamped enrichment programs by submitting new items for approval and observing the animals with the items for success and safety

## OTHER EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

# **Driver Growth Operations Associate**

#### Lyft (Jan 2017 - Jun 2018

- Utilized internal tools to take prospective drivers from application to their first passenger
- Conducted quality assurance, provided coaching to local teams and partner sites, and built out training decks for Tier 1 Support
- Created project proposals for areas of Lyft's processes that need improvement and presented proposals to stakeholders
- Learned basic SQL to query data used to implement and make improvements to the driver application process
- Conducted A/B tests to collect and analyze data to determine the success of proposed ideas of improvement

# **Front Desk Manager**

#### Climb Nashville (Feb 2016 - Dec 2016)

- Built relationships with members & guests by exchanging knowledge & experience about rock climbing
- Managed employees and the flow of the daily schedule to insure a safe and fun environment
- Used Rock Gym Pro software to add & edit member & guest information and to inventory all food, gear, & facility supplies
- Listened thoroughly and intently to members & guests in order to match them with the membership and gear that best fit their individual needs
- Documented any incidents or injuries in reports and participated in meetings with management to share ideas of how to approve gym safety

# **Summer Camp Coordinator**

## Nashville Zoo (Feb 2016 - Aug 2016)

- Managed summer camp staff and all aspects of summer camp including lessons, crafts, games, etc.
- Developed age-appropriate curriculum for multiple camps spanning ages 4-14
- Utilized Excel to organize camper registration information and create weekly rosters
- Presented exciting up close animal encounter presentations by using proper animal handling techniques and various interpretation styles
- Conducted evaluations on curriculum through surveys to assess the impact of the conservation messages that were taught
- Won 1st place in the Nashville Scene's 2016 Best of Nashville contest for best summer camp.

# **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Along with two fellow Hoofstock Keepers at the Nashville Zoo, I conducted a survey about giraffe and okapi husbandry practices across zoos worldwide and presented the results at the 2019 International Giraffid Conference at the Columbus Zoo.
- Furthered my professional development by obtaining a certification from the National Association for Interpretation as a Certified Interpretive Guide in Nov 2019.
- I had a poster displayed at the American Association of Zoo Keeper's National Chapter's 2015 Regional Symposium on the progress I made in establishing target training and desensitization training with the arapaima in the Smithsonian National Zoo's Amazonia exhibit.
- In 2013, I traveled to Karongwe Game Reserve in South Africa for a volunteer abroad program through GVI. I assisted with their reserve management by using telemetry to track implanted animals to collect data on the animal's location, behavior, full rating, and prey preference.
- In 2010, I traveled to the Amazon Rainforest in Peru for a Tropical Field Ecology course through Towson University where I conducted my own research project at Cocha Cashu Biological Station. I surveyed the bird species on both Cocha Cashu Lake and the Manu River to see if there was a significant difference in which species used which body of water and what they were using it for. I conducted statistical analysis using SPSS and wrote my findings in a research paper.